University Photograph; Collection ua390
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- A picture of Janice Friedman Keller, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1940 and Chairperson of the Alumni Council with Samuel E. Aronowitz, President of the Benevolent Association at an event associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, 1964. There are crop marks on all sides of the photograph.
- A picture of Louise Hastings as she takes her name tag at the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, 1964.
- A picture of Evan R. Collins (viewer's far left), President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, receiving visitors at the President's Reception associated with Alumni Day, 1964. There are crop marks on two sides of the photograph.
- A picture of John B. Laing, Jr., New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1954 with Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph) from July 1949-June 30, 1969. Laing was Chairperson for the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, 1964.
- A picture of State University of New York at Albany faculty standing under a pergola and preparing for the start of the 1964 commencement ceremony.
- An unidentified gentleman giving a speech at the State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony, 1964.
- An unidentified gentleman giving a speech at the State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony, 1964.
- A picture of (viewer's left to right) Randolph Gardner, Evan R. Collins, an unidentified gentleman, and Louis Wolner, Sr. Collins was President of the State University of New York at Albany from July 1949-June 30, 1969. The event is taking place in association with the 1964 commencement.
- A picture of Walter M. Tisdale, member of the State University of New York at Albany faculty., 1964 March 5
- Evan R. Collins [President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969] and faculty at a plaque presentation to the State University College at Oneonta (the first headquarters for the American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education) and Charles W. Hunt, Oneonta's President from 1942 -1951 and the AACTR's first secretary-treasurer. The plaque was presented on the occasion of the Twelfth Biennial School for Executives. Collins is on the viewer's far right., 1964 August
- Attending the 1965 State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony are graduating students on both sides of an aisle and a speaker at the podium in the background. Duplicate of 2484.
- Members of the class of 1935 seated at their thirtieth reunion. Includes Professor Robert Fredericks, Ruth Hilkert Gaffga, David Kroman, Susan Seabury Smith, Hilda Heins Ruuz., 1965
- A portrait of Lannie M. Graham, State University of New York at Albany, Class of 1965.
- Aerial view of the construction of the State University of New York at Albany Uptown Campus. In the background construction is in progress on the Academic Podium and the Colonial Quadrangle. In the foreground construction is completed on the Dutch Quadrangle in the center and service buildings to the left. The service buildings are the location of the Power Plant and Physical Plant., 1965
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, posing in front of the small fountain just outside the Campus Center of the uptown campus., 1965
- A picture of State University of New York at Albany Alumni Association members of the Metropolitan Chapter. Pictured are branch officers, seated (left to right): Daniel J. Kelly, Class of 1953 and 1954; Jean Pulver Hague, Class of 1949; and Bernadette Freel Rydell, Class of 1950; standing (left to right): Arthur J. Cornwell, Class of 1947 and 1948; and Benjamin A. Jackson, Class of 1950. All are graduates of the New York State College for Teachers., 1965
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, seated., 1965
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, at the Golden Eye Coffee House -- once located in a Presbyterian Church on Madison Avenue -- meeting with young adults, perhaps students. Collins is to the left, in full profile without glasses., 1965
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, with faculty members Edith O. Wallace, Carolyn H. Howard, and Ellen C. Stokes at an event associated with Alumni Day, 1965.
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, speaking to an unidentified woman., 1965
- Attending the 1965 State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony are graduating students on both sides of an aisle and a speaker at the podium in the background. Duplicate of 2483.
- A group of unidentified students participating in the 1965 State University of New York commencement procession. There are crop marks in the bottom and left margins.
- Faculty members attending the 1965 State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony.
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, posing in front of the small fountain just outside the Campus Center of the uptown campus., 1965
- A group photograph of the Statesmen, a men's singing group of the State University of New York at Albany. In the year of this photo, 1965, they were directed by Prof. Karl A. B. Peterson of the Music Department (standing front and center) with Nicholas Argyros accompanying (at the piano). This photo is from page 152 of the 1965 Torch yearbook. In the first row: G. Proulx, J. Drapalski, H. Mueller, J. Robb, J. Mormile, E. Piening, J. Oliver; second row: G. Castagliola, P. Cochrane, G. Nicosia, D. Simington, J. Monte, J. Johnville, M. Moody; third row: A. Putman, F. E. Tobey, K. Darmer, S. Kliman, C. Sand, T. Alcamo, D. Prockup, and R. Matrese.
- Max Lerner, professor of American Civilization at Brandeis University, speaking at the 1965 State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony. Duplicate of 1371.
- A portrait of Max Lerner, professor of American Civilization at Brandeis University, speaking at the 1965 State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony. Negative available. Duplicate of 4152.
- A picture from a Telethon event with Sorrell E. Chesin at the microphone. The Telethon was held in one of the buildings on the uptown campus. Chesin has been active in the institution's Office of Parent Relations, as Associate Vice President for University Advancement, and is listed in Who's Who in the Leadership of the United States., 1965
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, at the Golden Eye Coffee House -- once located in a Presbyterian Church on Madison Avenue -- meeting with young adults, perhaps students. Collins is somewhat center in the photograph., 1965
- A picture of the procession of students at the State University of New York at Albany's Torch Night, 1965. The event is taking place on the downtown campus. Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany from August 1962 from July 1949-June 30, 1969, is the gentleman standing beside the column in academic costume.
- A picture showing the procession of students during the Torch Night event., 1965
- A group photograph of the Statesmen, a men's singing group of the State University of New York at Albany, during a performance in their 1965-1966 season. They were directed by Prof. Karl A. B. Peterson of the Music Department.
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, making a speech., 1965
- An unidentified student accepting her diploma during the 1965 State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony. Evan R. Collins, President of the university from June 1949-June 30, 1969, stands at the viewer's right. Female student reciving diploma, Evan Collins seen at right of podium An unidentified student receiving a diploma during commmencement.
- A picture of Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany from July 1949-June 30, 1969, presenting an unidentified student with a diploma during the 1965 State University of New York commencement ceremony.
- The Statesmen, a men's singing group of the State University of New York at Albany. In the year of this photo, 1965, they were directed by Prof. Karl A. B. Peterson of the Music Department (standing front and center) with Nicholas Argyros accompanying (at the piano). This photo is from page 152 of the 1965 Torch yearbook. In the first row: G. Proulx, J. Drapalski, H. Mueller, J. Robb, J. Mormile, E. Piening, J. Oliver; second row: G. Castagliola, P. Cochrane, G. Nicosia, D. Simington, J. Monte, J. Johnville, M. Moody; third row: A. Putman, F. E. Tobey, K. Darmer, S. Kliman, C. Sand, T. Alcamo, D. Prockup, and R. Matrese.
- A portrait of Clifton C. Thorne, former Vice President of Student Affairs of the State University of New York at Albany. Thorne is credited with creating the Univeristy College, which was established for freshmen and sophomore students giving them the opportunity to explore a wide variety of subjects before declaring a major course of study., 1965
- A picture of the procession of students at the State University of New York at Albany's Torch Night, 1965. The event is taking place on the downtown campus. Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany from August 1962 from July 1949-June 30, 1969, is the gentleman standing beside the column in academic costume.
- A picture of Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany from July 1949-June 30, 1969, presenting an unidentified student with a diploma during the 1965 State University of New York commencement ceremony.
- Ruth Hilkert Gaffga and Professor Robert Fredericks seated at the class of 1935 thirtieth reunion in 1965.
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969. He is with Janet R. Grodon (on the viewer's left, shaking hands with Collins) and Mrs. Lyle J. Howland in the center., 1965
- Pictured are, left to right: Clifton C. Thorne, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1949, an unidentified woman, and Eunice B. Whittlesey, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1944. They are standing on the Academic Podium of the uptown campus, facing north. Thorne is credited with creating the Univeristy College, which was established for freshmen and sophomore students giving them the opportunity to explore a wide variety of subjects before declaring a major course of study. Duplicate of 1555., 1965
- A musical group performance being televised during the Cavalcade of Talent Telethon. The Telethon was held in a building on the uptown campus., 1965
- A picture of State University of New York at Albany Alumni Association members of the Metropolitan Chapter. Pictured are branch officers, seated (left to right): Daniel J. Kelly, Class of 1953 and 1954; Jean Pulver Hague, Class of 1949; and Bernadette Freel Rydell, Class of 1950; standing (left to right): Arthur J. Cornwell, Class of 1947 and 1948; and Benjamin A. Jackson, Class of 1950. All are graduates of the New York State College for Teachers., 1965
- A picture of Susann Winnie Steinberg, State University of New York College at Albany, Class of 1962, as she receives the Hoffman?Laroche Prize for "Most Outstanding Promise in Medicine" from Dr. Harold C. Wiggers, Dean of Albany Medical College. There are crop marks on all sides of the photograph and in the bottom margin is written "1 1/2 x 2.", 1965
- A picture of State University of New York at Albany faculty members Edith O. Wallace, Carolyn H. Howard, and Ellen C. Stokes. They are pictured with Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the institution at the time of this event) from July 1949-June 30, 1969. The event is taking place in association with Alumni Day, 1965.
- At an event associated with commencement, an unidentified speaker announcing Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the institution at the time of this event) from July 1949 until June 30, 1969. Collins' back is to the camera., 1965
- Faculty participating in the 1965 State University of New York at Albany commencement ceremony. Duplicate of 1222. Written in the bottom margin is "crop G576 Flop 48%."
- A group portrait of State University of New York at Albany faculty during an event associated with commencement. Duplicate of 1346., 1965
- Unidentified students receiving their diplomas during commmencement. Duplicate of 1344., 1965
- A picture of State University of New York at Albany Alumni Association members. Pictured are, left to right: Clifton C. Thorne, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1949, an unidentified woman, and Eunice B. Whittlesey, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1944. They are standing on the Academic Podium of the uptown campus, facing north., 1965
- A picture showing the procession of students during the Torch Night event., 1965
- Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969 at the Uptown Campus., 1965
- New Campus Architect Views Work, Stone Reacts Favorably to Buildings by Harold Lynne of the ASP. An article regarding Edward Durell Stone's visit to the State University of New York at Albany Uptown Campus. In the article Stone expresses pride in his design after taking a tour of the buildings constucted to date. Writing in the bottom margin includes "ASP" and "1/12/65"., 1965 January 12
- Class of 1965 seated during University at Albany's commencement., 1965 May 1
- Construction of the University Library for the State University of New York at Albany Uptown Campus. The photograph was taken looking west to the University Library at ground level, showing the stairwell to the second floor of the library. This photograph came from the office of Edward Durell Stone who was the architect who designed the Uptown Campus. This photograph is fixed with a canvas back. On the back there are date stamps showing that the photograph went from the office of architect Edward Durell Stone to the New York State University Construction Fund. Writing in the left margin includes "SUCF 01-02 * Basic Construction Co.* Academic Bldgs. I * Library Bldg. looking West into court, showing stairs & tall columns," "June 9 1965" and "by E. M. Weil"., 1965 June 9
- A transparency of four photographs all of which are depicting events associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965. Janice Friedman Keller, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1940 is the person in the center of photographs two through four (top to bottom)., 1965 June 12
- A group portrait of twenty-one unidentified people gathered for an event associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of Margaret Morey Cunningham, New York State Normal College, Class of 1896, as she receives the award for Highest Percentage of Class Attendance. The event is taking place in association with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of mostly unidentified people at an event associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965. The gentleman on the viewer's far right is Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the institution at the time of the event) from July 1949-June 30, 1969., 1965 June 12
- A picture of State University of New York at Albany faculty members Edith O. Wallace, Carolyn H. Howard, and Ellen C. Stokes. They are pictured with Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the institution at the time of this event) from July 1949-June 30, 1969. The event is taking place in association with Alumni Day, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of members of the New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1915 on the occasion of their fiftieth reunion during State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day festivities, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of three people, two of which are unidentified. The woman in the center is Janice Friedman Keller, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1940. They are gathered at an event associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of members of the New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1915 on the occasion of their fiftieth reunion during State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day festivities, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of an unidentified woman who is making a speech at an event associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of members of the New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1915 on the occasion of their fiftieth reunion during State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day festivities, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of Janice Friedman Keller, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1940, and Evan R. Collins (viewer's far right), President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the institution at the time of this event) from July 1949-June 30, 1969. The other two gentlemen are unidentified. They are all participating in an awards event associated with Alumni Day, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of mostly unidentified people, one of whom is receiving an award associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965. The gentleman in the center is Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the institution at the time of the event) from July 1949-June 30, 1969., 1965 June 12
- A group portrait of unidentified gentlemen -- perhaps students or faculty -- posing in caps and gowns at an event associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- A picture of a large number of people at a dinner banquet associated with the State University of New York at Albany Alumni Day, June 12, 1965., 1965 June 12
- Scene from a reception on the uptown campus' Academic Podium for visiting speaker, U Thant, who served as Secretary-General of the United Nations from 1961 to 1971. At the time of his appointment as Acting Secretary-General of the United Nations, U Thant had been Permanent Representative of Burma to the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador (1957-1961). He visited the university on the occasion of the University Seminar on Peaceful Changes, 1966.
- Fannie Hall Delameter, New York State College for Teachers, Class of 1932. She is at an Open House event in celebration of her retirement in 1966.
- The goalie on the State University of New York at Albany soccer team attempted to block a shot in a game against Potsdam., 1966
- A large crowd of students waiting to register for classes in Draper Hall at the State University of New York at Albany on the downtown campus. This image appeared in the ASP, May 6, 1966, pg.1 with the caption "Students crowded into the first and second floor halls of Draper on Monday to stand in line in order to obtain the courses they wanted next semester." There are crop marks in the right and bottom margins of the original.
- Scene from a reception on the uptown campus' Academic Podium for visiting speaker, U Thant, who served as Secretary-General of the United Nations from 1961 to 1971. At the time of his appointment as Acting Secretary-General of the United Nations, U Thant had been Permanent Representative of Burma to the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador (1957-1961). He visited the university on the occasion of the University Seminar on Peaceful Changes, 1966.
- The Torch Night procession of 1966, held at the downtown campus of the State University of New York at Albany.
- The Torch Night procession of 1966, held at the downtown campus of the State University of New York at Albany.
- A group photograph of the Statesmen, a men's singing group of the State University of New York at Albany. They were directed by Prof. Karl A. B. Peterson of the Music Department (standing front and center)., 1966
- A group photograph of the Statesmen, a men's singing group of the State University of New York at Albany. They were directed by Prof. Karl A. B. Peterson of the Music Department (standing front and center). The interior is that of a building on the uptown campus., 1966
- Visiting speaker, U Thant, who served as Secretary-General of the United Nations from 1961 to 1971. At the time of his appointment as Acting Secretary-General of the United Nations, U Thant had been Permanent Representative of Burma to the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador (1957-1961). He visited the university on the occasion of the University Seminar on Peaceful Changes, 1966. Evan R. Collins, President of the State University of New York at Albany (the name of the university at the time of this photograph and was so from August 1962 until the fall of 1986) from July 1949-June 30, 1969, is the gentleman seated directly behind Thant with his arms crossed.
- A group photograph of the Statesmen from the 1966-1967 season, a men's singing group of the State University of New York at Albany. They were directed by Prof. Karl A. B. Peterson of the Music Department (standing in the front row, sixth from the viewer's left).
- Visiting speaker, U Thant, who served as Secretary-General of the United Nations from 1961 to 1971. At the time of his appointment as Acting Secretary-General of the United Nations, U Thant had been Permanent Representative of Burma to the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador (1957-1961). He visited the university on the occasion of the University Seminar on Peaceful Changes, 1966. In this picture, Thant is at the podium and is difficult to see behind the watermark on the photograph.